<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Sakigake English</title>
    <link>https://www.sakigake.jp/</link>
    <description>Local Akita News in English by Sakigake</description>
    <managingEditor>aubrey@michaelcharl.es (Michael Charles Aubrey)</managingEditor>
    <pubDate>Wed, 24 Mar 2021 18:16:42 +0900</pubDate>
    <item>
      <title>A Group of 40 Monkeys In a Field In Kita-Akita, Seeking Food In a Village?</title>
      <link>https://news.line.me/issue/oa-sakigake/lv7cpicijyeq</link>
      <description>　Around 10 a.m. on the 23rd, a man in the neighborhood saw about 40 monkeys in a field in Tsujiko, Kita-Akita City, Akita Prefecture. Around 4 p.m., several more monkeys appeared again. No damage was done. &lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt; According to Mr. Masashi Ogasawara (45), a farmer who witnessed the event, when he went outside from his farm shed in the morning of the same day, he saw monkeys climbing on the frame of a plastic house and trees, and walking in the field. In the evening, it appeared in the woods and fields near his house. It disappeared into the woods to the southwest. It was about 50 centimeters long. &lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt; In Ohata village, north of Godi village, where Mr. Ogasawara lives, monkeys have been appearing, targeting food offered at graves during the spring equinox. It was the first time I&#39;d seen so many monkeys in my neighborhood,&#34; he said. I was upset because I&#39;ve never seen so many monkeys in my neighborhood before, and I&#39;m worried about whether they will affect our farm work in the future. &lt;br/&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Mar 2021 18:16:16 +0900</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Title</title>
      <link>https://news.line.me/list/oa-sakigake/i5i6com1xhk4/rsgaqkcit686</link>
      <description>The introduction of nursing care robots and information and communications technology (ICT) into elderly care facilities and other facilities has been attracting attention in recent years in order to reduce the physical burden on nursing care workers and improve work efficiency. The national and prefectural governments are also encouraging the introduction of these robots, and the prefecture has been holding a nursing care robot exhibition since fiscal 2018. &lt;br/&gt; In fiscal 2008, vendors of nursing care equipment promoted their latest devices to nursing care service facility staff and others, and personnel from nursing care facilities that have introduced the devices reported on case studies. &lt;br/&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Mar 2021 18:16:18 +0900</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Local PR Bread, Odate Is Akita Dog Daily Yamazaki</title>
      <link>https://news.line.me/issue/oa-sakigake/6efsl8yf9boc</link>
      <description>　At the Daily Yamazaki Odate Higashidai convenience store in Odate City, Akita Prefecture, bread with an illustration of an Akita dog is popular. &lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt; Daily Yamazaki stores around the country are promoting their local areas by selling bread with original branding. Most of them are branded with only the name of the place and few with illustrations. &lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt; The Dongdae store also had only the word &#34;Dongdae&#34; when it started in 2015, but changed to the current design in time for the Year of the Dog in 2006. &lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt; The bread comes in three varieties, including an whipped bean paste (155 yen), and the company says it sells about 70 a day.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Mar 2021 18:16:22 +0900</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Shoyo and Komatsu Coach Noshiro Integrated School Basketball Team, Noko HC Ono Resigns</title>
      <link>https://news.line.me/issue/oa-sakigake/hwxx2v9zor1e</link>
      <description>　It was announced on April 23 that Gen Komatsu, 48, a basketball coach at Noshiro Shoyo High School, will become the head coach of the men&#39;s basketball team at Noshiro Science and Technology High School, which will open next month after the merger of Noshiro Technical High School and Noshiro Nishi High School. &lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt; Shuji Ono, 63, the head coach (HC) of the Noshiro Technical High School basketball team, will step down when his term as a technical advisor (TA) for the prefectural sports association ends at the end of fiscal 2020. &lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt; Komatsu, a Yokote High School-Kanazawa University graduate, was appointed to Noshiro Shoyo High School in 2001 and served as the coach of the prefecture&#39;s boys&#39; and girls&#39; basketball teams at the Wakayama National Athletic Meet in 2003, Ehime National Athletic Meet in 2005 and Fukui National Athletic Meet in 2006.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Mar 2021 18:16:27 +0900</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Workplace Cluster Outbreak of Corona Infection In a Woman In the Jurisdiction of Daisen Public Health Center</title>
      <link>https://news.line.me/issue/oa-sakigake/jzakfwew9qg8</link>
      <description>　On the 23rd, Akita Prefecture announced that a female employee in her 30s in the jurisdiction of the Daisen Public Health Center was infected with a new type of coronavirus, a colleague of a male employee in his 30s whose infection was announced on the 16th. &lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt; The number of confirmed infected people in this workplace has increased to five, and the prefecture said that a cluster (group of infected people) has occurred in the workplace. The total number of infected people in the prefecture is 278. &lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt; According to the prefectural government, the woman was tested for PCR as a close contact on the 16th and tested negative, but had symptoms such as a sore throat and fever from the 20th, and was tested again on the 22nd and found to be positive. She was not seriously ill and was admitted to a residential treatment facility on the 23rd.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Mar 2021 18:16:32 +0900</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Plaza Geihin (Yokote) Tops the Rakuten Travel &#34;Japan&#39;S Hotel Award&#34; In Akita.</title>
      <link>https://news.line.me/issue/oa-sakigake/ptgeb97rpo86</link>
      <description>　In Akita Prefecture, Yokote Onsen Hotel Plaza Gebin (Yokote City) has been selected as one of the Top 47 hotels in the Rakuten Travel Japan Inn Awards 2020, which are given to the top-performing hotels in each prefecture. This is the first time that the hotel has been selected for the TOP 47. &lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt; Rakuten Travel is a comprehensive travel site that handles travel, hotel and tour reservations, airline ticket and car rental reservations, and tourism information dissemination. &lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt; Hotel Plaza Geihin was evaluated for the quality of its restaurants and other facilities, as well as the content of word-of-mouth reviews of its customer service. 19 rooms in total, accommodating two to six people. The hotel has a total of 19 rooms that can accommodate two to six people, and its popularity is due to the fact that private rooms and private baths can be used to spend time with family members alone, and that guests can enjoy a sense of luxury. &lt;br/&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Mar 2021 18:16:36 +0900</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Voting on Buses In Yuzawa City, a First Attempt to Secure Opportunities</title>
      <link>https://news.line.me/issue/oa-sakigake/zt691bm3zvxa</link>
      <description>　The Election Commission of Yuzawa City, Akita Prefecture, will open mobile polling stations by bus and operate free taxis to ensure voting opportunities in areas where it has been decided to reduce the number of polling stations for the Yuzawa mayoral election to be held on March 28 and April 4. &lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt; In September last year, the city election commission decided to reduce the number of polling places from 61 to 28 in view of the increase in the number of early voting. Of these, mobile polling stations will be opened in 14 areas with a high voter turnout and in 14 areas with a large number of voters, and shared taxis will be used in almost all of the areas that have been eliminated. &lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt; The mobile polling stations will be held for four days from March 30 to April 2, using a total of two small and medium-sized buses of a private bus company. The buses will be equipped with a writing table and ballot boxes and will be open for two hours per location.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Mar 2021 18:16:39 +0900</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ongoing Woes In Downtown Kawasan and Sanno Walking the Streets at Night with Few Lights</title>
      <link>https://news.line.me/issue/oa-sakigake/rvecm12jfovm</link>
      <description>　Restaurants in downtown Akita City&#39;s Kawasan and Sanno areas continue to suffer from the effects of the new coronavirus. From last month to this month, a reporter walked the streets at night with few lights. &lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt; The curtain of night has fallen on Kawasan. A sign saying &#34;Closed&#34; or &#34;For Rent&#34; is conspicuously displayed on an unlit shop. Taxis lined the street, their drivers lying down with their seats folded over. &lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt; At around 7 p.m., there are no customers in the pub on the first floor of the building. When I sat down at the counter and asked about the current state of the restaurant, the owner, 53, her expression clouded over. I feel sick to my stomach every day when I think about whether I can continue to run the shop. &lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;In Sanno, many shops were not lit up. There are very few people passing by. &lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt; At around 7 p.m., I entered a bar with a relaxed atmosphere on the second floor of the building. I&#39;m not sure what to make of it, but I think it&#39;s a good idea.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Mar 2021 18:16:42 +0900</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss> <nil>
